<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>		
		<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com</link>
		<atom:link href="https://www.pmhc-mds.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS - Change to login workflow - introduction of MFA - 16/10/2024</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;As per our recent communication, to enhance data security Logicly will be 
releasing the new Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) login workflow change 
on Monday 11th November 2024. The details sent originally are included again below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@logicly.com.au&quot;&gt;support@logicly.com.au&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC-MDS team at Logicly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-change-to-login-workflow&quot;&gt;PMHC-MDS - Change to login workflow - introduction of MFA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Logicly’s ongoing commitment to data security and in response to
the Australian Signals Directorate’s Information Security Manual guidance, 
we are rolling out Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) to all users that 
access the PMHC-MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-what-is-changing&quot;&gt;What is changing?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After entering your username and password you will be required to complete 
a second authentication step. MFA is an additional layer of authentication 
that works by requiring users to provide verification information (via a 
device they have) in addition to their email address/password (which they 
know) when logging in. Taken together these multiple “factors” are used 
to verify the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logicly’s authentication system supports a variety of additional factors, 
including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push notifications sent to an application on the user’s smart mobile 
device&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One-time passcodes generated by an application such as Google 
Authenticator and entered by the user during login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB Security Keys which support WebAuthn with FIDO. These are connected 
to the users computer and touched during login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a user guide that will help step users through different options 
and how to set them up: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.logicly.com.au/en/latest/mfa-user-guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.logicly.com.au/en/latest/mfa-user-guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-when-will-this-happen&quot;&gt;When will this happen?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logicly intends to release this change on 11th November 2024.  A reminder 
email will be sent in the days prior to the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-why-is-this-happening&quot;&gt;Why is this happening?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change is being made in order to meet security improvements around the 
authentication and authorisation process for the PMHC-MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@logicly.com.au&quot;&gt;support@logicly.com.au&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC-MDS team at Logicly&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/11/06/PMHC-MDS-Reminder-of-change-to-login-workflow-introduction-of-MFA/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/11/06/PMHC-MDS-Reminder-of-change-to-login-workflow-introduction-of-MFA/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 1/11/2024 (v2.14.2)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2142&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.14.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.14.2 was released on 
November 1, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Department of Health and Aged Care’s October 2024 PHN CEO 
Circular, the PMHC MDS has been updated to support the capture of data 
at a more granular level in cases where a provider organisation operates 
out of multiple sites within the same PHN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new ‘Sites’ tab is available in the data entry interface for Provider 
Organisations. This tab allows sites for the provider organisation to be
defined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where sites have been defined for a Provider Organisation, a drop down 
list containing each of the sites is now displayed on the Service Contact 
tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Service Contact Modality field now includes “SMS”. Please refer to the
notes at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/latest/data-model-and-specifications.html#modality&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/latest/data-model-and-specifications.html#modality&lt;/a&gt;
for advice on how this response may be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upload interface now accepts uploads in the Version 4.1 data 
specification. This specification allows the capture of a provider
organisation operating at multiple sites within the same PHN.
Please see below for more information on this specification. The existing 
Version 4.0 data specification will continue to be available until 1 May 2025. 
After that date it will no longer be available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upload interface also accepts the Version 4.0.5 data specification. This 
specification allows for the capture of “SMS” in the Service Contact 
Modality field. The new Version 4.1 data specification also includes this
update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following update has been made to the PMHC MDS user interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Idle session detection has been improved. Interacting with screen elements, 
for example by typing or clicking, will extend user session timeouts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-data-specification-version-41&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specification Version 4.1&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Data Specification update v4.1 was released on November 1 2024. 
The following updates were implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sites - Added sites field to the Organisation record to allow the sites at 
which a provider organisation provides services to clients to be specified&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service Contact Site - Added site field to the Service Contact record to 
allow the site at which a Service Contact took place to be specified&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modality - Added response ‘5: SMS’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-data-specification-update-version-405&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specification Update Version 4.0.5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Data Specification update v4.0.5 was released on November 1 2024. 
The following updates were implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modality - Added response ‘5: SMS’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/11/01/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-14-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/11/01/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-14-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Sites Field in the PMHC MDS</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The below circular was sent to PHN CEOs in October 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHN CEO Circular October 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-sites-field-in-the-pmhc-mds&quot;&gt;New Sites Field in the PMHC MDS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;overview-2024x10&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular is to inform you about an upcoming addition to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS) that will allow for data to be captured at a more granular level in cases where a provider organisation operates out of multiple sites within the same PHN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be done by implementing a new data field called “sites” to the service contact record. The sites field will be available for all PHNs to use but is only a mandatory field for Medicare Mental Health Centres (MMHCs, formerly Head to Health) to enable more accurate routine program monitoring of these services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information on the new sites field.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share the guidance regarding the new sites field with relevant staff and service providers by 31 October 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Begin uploading to the PMHC MDS under v4.1 by 30 April 2025 before the v4.0 specification is phased out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all Medicare Mental Health Centres are named according to the guidance provided in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any questions regarding this information please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;background-2024x10&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provision of information via the PMHC MDS is necessary for governments to undertake their role in funding, monitoring, and planning future national service delivery. The introduction of the new sites field aims to address the limitation that occurs when the same Provider Organisation (PO) is delivering services across multiple ‘sites’ within a PHN region. For each MMHC, a ‘site’ may be defined as a PO’s distinct service venue where there is more than one MMHC within the PHN region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2023, the department consulted PHNs via the Head to Health Data Leads Community of Practice about the proposed new sites field in the PMHC MDS. Overall, the solution was supported. Some PHNs noted it could also be helpful for contract management and monitoring of other programs. At this stage, implementation of the new sites field is only mandatory for MMHCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For services that are not required to follow the MMHC naming guidance, a ‘site’ may be interpreted as a mechanism to differentiate activity occurring within a PO either physically, functionally, or contractually where PHNs feel this is the most appropriate way to record their data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;addition-technical-details-2024x10&quot;&gt;Additional Technical details&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If PHNs wish to begin system preparation in advance the draft specification is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Draft PMHC MDS Data Specification 4.1.0-Draft documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sites field will be introduced with the release of PMHC MDS specification v4.1 which is anticipated to occur in November 2024. PHNs are encouraged to begin submitting data to v4.1 as soon as convenient but to allow for the transition v4.0 will not be decommissioned until April 2025. By this date, all PHNs and/or their service providers that upload to the PMHC MDS will need to upgrade to v4.1 before the v4.0 specification is phased out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;POs will have the ability to create sites for their organisation. Relevant staff may define the list of sites via upload or data entry. For data entry, the sites field will only be displayed on the Service Contact data entry form if there are sites defined for a PO. If there are sites defined for a PO, the service_contact_site field must be one of the defined sites of the PO. If there are no sites defined for a PO, the data entry form will not have any changes to how it currently appears for the v4.0 specification. The Logicly help desk is available to support PHNs with technical questions in relation to the implementation of the sites field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The addition of the sites field does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; apply to data submitted under the WayBack extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;naming-guidance-2024x10&quot;&gt;Naming Guidance&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;mmhc-2024x10&quot;&gt;MMHC&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;POs should ensure that site names are clear and easily distinguishable from other MMHCs and services in their PHN region. To support accurate reporting and monitoring of service activity data through the PMHC MDS, it is recommended that the MMHC location is included in the site name (e.g., Townsville MMHC should include ‘Townsville’ somewhere in the site name such as TOWNSVILLE2024). Where a single MMHC is operating across more than one location, it is at the discretion of the PO whether to include this level of detail in the site name. PHNs can contact the Department &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;(MentalHealthData@health.gov.au)&lt;/a&gt; to discuss individual requirements about implementing the MMHC naming guidance, as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;other-2024x10&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHNs and POs who wish to utilise the sites field for services that are not delivered through MMHCs are requested to name sites in a reasonable and sensible way that maintains confidentiality for the relevant provider and complies with privacy legislation.   Logicly have updated the guidance available via the PMHC MDS data specification to include general naming guidance and validation requirements for the sites field: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Draft PMHC MDS Data Specification 4.1.0-Draft documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;action-required-2024x10&quot;&gt;Action Required&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The v4.1 specification is planned for release from 1 November 2024. PHNs will be notified through a system release e-mail notification from Logicly’s PMHC-MDS support service. Once released, PHNs will need to ensure that this information is distributed to relevant staff and service providers, and that their processes are updated accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHNs are encouraged to begin submitting data under PMHC MDS specification v4.1 once it is released. For a 6-month period from the v4.1 release date, the PMHC MDS will still accept the v4.0 upload format before it is phased out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For technical support, please contact Logicly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/10/27/New-Sites-Field-in-the-PMHC-MDS/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/10/27/New-Sites-Field-in-the-PMHC-MDS/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 20/10/2024 (v2.13.7)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2137&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.13.7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.13.7 was released on 
October 20, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the speed of the A1, B1, B2, B3 reports based on PHN and 
Provider Organisation level of reporting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the validation message when there are missing columns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/10/20/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-13-7/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/10/20/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-13-7/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS - Change to login workflow - introduction of MFA - 16/10/2024</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds---change-to-login-workflow---introduction-of-mfa&quot;&gt;PMHC-MDS - Change to login workflow - introduction of MFA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Logicly’s ongoing commitment to data security and in response to
the Australian Signals Directorate’s Information Security Manual guidance, 
we are rolling out Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) to all users that 
access the PMHC-MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-introduction-what-is-changing&quot;&gt;What is changing?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After entering your username and password you will be required to complete 
a second authentication step. MFA is an additional layer of authentication 
that works by requiring users to provide verification information (via a 
device they have) in addition to their email address/password (which they 
know) when logging in. Taken together these multiple “factors” are used 
to verify the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logicly’s authentication system supports a variety of additional factors, 
including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push notifications sent to an application on the user’s smart mobile 
device&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One-time passcodes generated by an application such as Google 
Authenticator and entered by the user during login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB Security Keys which support WebAuthn with FIDO. These are connected 
to the users computer and touched during login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a user guide that will help step users through different options 
and how to set them up: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.logicly.com.au/en/latest/mfa-user-guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.logicly.com.au/en/latest/mfa-user-guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-introduction-when-will-this-happen&quot;&gt;When will this happen?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logicly intends to release this change on 11th November 2024.  A reminder 
email will be sent in the days prior to the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-introduction-why-is-this-happening&quot;&gt;Why is this happening?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change is being made in order to meet security improvements around the 
authentication and authorisation process for the PMHC-MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@logicly.com.au&quot;&gt;support@logicly.com.au&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC-MDS team at Logicly&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/10/16/PMHC-MDS-Change-to-login-workflow-introduction-of-MFA/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/10/16/PMHC-MDS-Change-to-login-workflow-introduction-of-MFA/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 11/8/2024 (v2.13.0)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2130&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.13.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.13.0 was released on August 1, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As previously advised, Version 2 of the Initial Assessment and Referral Decision Support 
Tool can now be recorded in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 2 includes separate rating guides available for use with Children (aged 5-11), 
Adolescents (aged 12-17), Adults (aged 18-64), Older Adults (aged 65 and over). 
More information regarding IAR-DST Version 2 is available via the official IAR-DST
v2 specification documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.iar-dst.online/en/v2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.iar-dst.online/en/v2/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS data entry interface will now accept either Version 1 or Version 2 of the IAR-DST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Version 1 and Version 2 of the IAR-DST can now be uploaded to the PMHC MDS using the 
v4.0.4 data specification. v4.0.4 is backwards compatible with the existing v4 
specifications. Therefore, any organisations that are not yet ready to collect IAR-DST 
Version 2 data, can continue to upload with their current file format. The v4.0.4 
data specification is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific information about implementing Version 2 of the IAR-DST is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/data-model-and-specifications.html#iar-dst&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/data-model-and-specifications.html#iar-dst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/08/11/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-13-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/08/11/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-13-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS IAR-DST Version 2 and Outcome Measures Standard Deviations - 09/08/2024</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-iar-dst-version-2-update&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS IAR-DST Version 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From early next week, Version 2 of the Initial Assessment and Referral 
Decision Support Tool will be able to be recorded in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 2 includes separate rating guides available for use with 
Children (aged 5-11), Adolescents (aged 12-17), Adults (aged 18-64), 
Older Adults (aged 65 and over). More information regarding IAR-DST 
Version 2 is available via the official IAR-DST v2 specification 
documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.iar-dst.online/en/v2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.iar-dst.online/en/v2/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upgraded, the PMHC MDS data entry interface will accept either Version 1 or
Version 2 of the IAR-DST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Version 1 and Version 2 of the IAR-DST will be able to be uploaded 
to the PMHC MDS using the v4.0.4 data specification. v4.0.4 is backwards 
compatible with the existing v4 specifications. Therefore, any organisations 
that are not yet ready to collect IAR-DST Version 2 data, can continue to 
upload with their current file format. The v4.0.4 data specification is 
already available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific information about implementing Version 2 of the IAR-DST is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/data-model-and-specifications.html#iar-dst&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/data-model-and-specifications.html#iar-dst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A further announcement will be made when Version 2 of the IAR-DST is available
in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The v4.0.4 data specification differs from the v4.0.3 data specification in
that the 2.older value for the IAR-DST version field has been updated to
2.older-adult in order to make it consistent with the IAR-DST specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;outcome-measure-standard-deviations&quot;&gt;Outcome Measure Standard Deviations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some reports, such as the Out series reports, use extra inputs that cannot be 
generated locally. Logicly supplies these inputs at 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/reporting-arrangements.html#inputs-to-help-replicate-system-generated-reports&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/reporting-arrangements.html#inputs-to-help-replicate-system-generated-reports&lt;/a&gt;
in order to assist organisations who wish to replicate the system reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcome measure standard deviations for 2024 are now available at 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/reporting-arrangements.html#outcome-measure-standard-deviations&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/reporting-arrangements.html#outcome-measure-standard-deviations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/08/09/IAR-DST-V2-specification-release-outcome-measure-standard-deviations/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/08/09/IAR-DST-V2-specification-release-outcome-measure-standard-deviations/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Clarification and Update to the PMHC MDS - 30/7/2024 (v2.12.8)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;You may have seen a recent PMHC MDS notification that users from State 
and Territory Governments will now be given access to aggregate PMHC MDS 
reports. We wish to advise that this only means that the technical data 
systems of the PMHC MDS have been updated in order to allow for access to be 
granted. Sharing of the PMHC MDS with State and Territory Governments as per 
commitments under the National Mental Health and Suicide Prevention Agreement 
is being closely managed by the Department of Health and Aged Care and access 
will only be granted after the relevant State or Territory health 
department/agency has signed a Data Sharing Agreement and agreed to follow a 
Data Access Protocol. These documents describe roles and responsibilities for 
specific users within a State or Territory health department/agency to ensure 
PMHC MDS data is handled appropriately and safely. Further information will 
be provided by the Department in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2128&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.12.8&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.12.8 was released on July 30, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where reports using The Wayback data source returned the error 
message ‘An error occurred: bad report data source’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/07/30/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-12-8/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/07/30/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-12-8/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 29/7/2024 (v2.12.7)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2127&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.12.7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the bilateral agreements between the Commonwealth and State/Territory 
Governments, users from State and Territory Governments can now be given 
access to aggregate reports. For more information please refer to the updated 
guidance on client consent at 
https://pmhc-mds.com/doc/pmhc-consent-guidance-20240430.pdf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reports that allow state/territory breakdowns (A1, B1, B2, B3) now use 
the state/territory of the commissioning PHN rather than the state/territory 
of the provider organisation that delivered the service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The efficiency of some reports has been improved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provider organisations that are not active in the selected reporting period 
are now being filtered out of Provider Organisation drop down&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the B1 report where if you generated a B1 report down to the 
PO level and then filtered by a specific provider organisation, that filtering 
did not get applied to the total row of the report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied to the user management interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue that was causing inactive users to be inconsistently  listed 
in the User Auditing tab and the Edit Roles tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added a check to ensure that upload files have the appropriate extension for 
their file type, that is, zip files must have a .zip extension and excel 
files must have a .xlsx extension&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message for duplicate values for the Organisation Type 
Referred to at Episode Conclusion field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message when duplicate Service Contact Practitioners are 
recorded for a Service Contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the Upload API:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One API key can now be used to upload to multiple provider organisations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/07/29/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-12-7/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/07/29/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-12-7/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS IAR-DST Version 2 - 08/07/2024</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-iar-dst-version-2&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS IAR-DST Version 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 2 of the Initial Assessment and Referral Decision Support Tool has now
been finalised and will soon be able to be collected in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 2 includes separate rating guides available for use with Children (aged 5-11),
Adolescents (aged 12-17), Adults (aged 18-64), Older Adults (aged 65 and over).
More information regarding IAR-DST Version 2 is available via the official IAR-DST v2
specification documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.iar-dst.online/en/v2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.iar-dst.online/en/v2/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upgraded, the PMHC MDS data entry interface will accept either Version 1 or
Version 2 of the IAR-DST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Version 1 and Version 2 of the IAR-DST will be able to be uploaded to the
PMHC MDS using the v4.0.3 data specification. v4.0.3 is backwards compatible with
the existing v4 specifications. Therefore, any organisations that are not yet
ready to collect IAR-DST Version 2 data, can continue to upload with their current
file format. The v4.0.3 data specification is already available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.0.3/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.0.3/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific information about implementing Version 2 of the IAR-DST is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.0.3/data-model-and-specifications.html#iar-dst&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.0.3/data-model-and-specifications.html#iar-dst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A further announcement will be made when Version 2 of the IAR-DST is available
in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/07/08/IAR-DST-V2-specification-release/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2024/07/08/IAR-DST-V2-specification-release/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>