<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>		
		<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com</link>
		<atom:link href="https://www.pmhc-mds.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 23/2/2026 (v3.0.7)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v307&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v3.0.7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v3.0.7 was released on 
February 23, 2026.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where Psychosocial could still be used as a Principal 
Focus of Treatment for a new episode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AMHC is no longer a valid response for new Intakes/Episodes for 
the ’Organisation type referred to at Intake/Episode Conclusion‘ 
field, but is still allowed for existing records. The 
‘HeadtoHelp / HeadtoHealth’ is similar but is still allowed for 
new Intakes/Episodes for remaining temporary Head to Health 
Clinics in New South Wales and Victoria. Fixed a bug when 
displaying these fields where these options were applied to 
existing records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with the Veteran field defaulting to 
“not stated/not adequately described”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug with the UA Needs Identification worksheet name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2026/02/23/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-3-0-7/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2026/02/23/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-3-0-7/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS - Release of Version 5.0 for Upload and Data Entry - 18/12/2025 (v3.0.1)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v301&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v3.0.1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS v3.0.1 was released on 
December 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 5.0 of the data specification is now available through Data Entry,
Upload and Data Extracts in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 5.0 completes the rebranding of AMHC and Head to Health to MMHC and 
the rebranding of The Way Back to Universal Aftercare. Please refer to the 
Department of Health, Disability and Ageing Circular (DoHDA) at 
https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/
and the Introduction section of the Version 5.0 specification at 
https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v5.0/introduction.html 
for overviews of the new specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing data entered using the The Way Back Version 3 specification has 
been migrated to the Version 5.0 specification. You may wish to review your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;data-entry-2025x12x18&quot;&gt;Data Entry&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following changes have been made in the Data Entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “2: Head to Health” Program Type has been renamed to 2: Head to Health 
Clinic. This response is only to be used by remaining temporary Head to 
Health Clinics in New South Wales and Victoria. For all other organisations,
existing episodes using this response have been migrated to “8: MMHC”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “3: AMHC” Program Type has been retired. All existing episodes using 
this response have been migrated to “8: MMHC”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;References to The Way Back have been changed to Universal Aftercare.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Veteran field has been added to Intake and Episode records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Practitioner Reason for Override field as been added to the IAR-DS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new system tag !uaooh has been introduced. Please refer to the DoHDA 
circular above for information on how this tag can be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;upload-2025x12x18&quot;&gt;Upload&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uploads now support the Version 5.0.0 data specification as documented at 
https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v5.0/upload-specification.html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a six month transition period during which Version 5.0.0, 
Version 4.1 and The Way Back Support Service Version 3 will all be accepted. 
Version 4.1 and The Way Back Support Service Version 3 will no longer be 
supported after 30 June 2026.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the transition period, uploads in either the Version 4.1 or The Way 
Back Support Service Version 3 specification will be converted to Version 5.0 
during upload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v5.0/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html 
for a description of the changes between the Version 4.1 or The Way Back 
Support Service Version 3 and the new Version 5.0 specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;reporting-2025x12x18&quot;&gt;Reporting&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Data Source selector on the reporting interface has been updated to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove Head to Health&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove AMHC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add MMHC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove The Way Back&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add Universal Aftercare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wayback tab has been removed. The Wayback reports have been rebranded 
and moved to the standard reports tab as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;W1: Wayback Quarterly Report Template rebrand to W1:  Universal Aftercare 
Quarterly Report Template. The W1 can be accessed by selecting Universal 
Aftercare as the only Data Source.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The W2: High level summary of overall volumes by entity report has been
retired. Counts of Universal Aftercare records can now be accessed via
the existing A1 report.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;W3: Data Quality Report: Missing TWB Episode data rebranded to 
A14: Data quality report - Missing UA Episode data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;W4: Data Quality Report: Missing TWB Needs Identification and Recommendation 
Outs rebranded to A15: Data quality report - Missing UA Needs Identification 
and Recommendation Outs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following new reports have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new A13: Data quality report — Universal Aftercare episodes with no linked 
UA episode record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M1: Client wait time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M2: Activity Reports by Age group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M3: Activity Reports by Gender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M4: Activity Reports by Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander status&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M5: IAR-DST - Recommended Level of Care&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M6: IAR-DST - Recommended Level of Care, where intake referred to MMHC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M7: Monthly service activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M8: Episode of care characteristics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M9: Activity Report: Service contact type&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;M10: Activity Report: Service contact duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports can now be filtered with the new !uaooh tag. Reports can no longer be 
filtered with the !wayback tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;known-issues&quot;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Version 5.0 format, Program Type 2: Head to Health Clinic is only 
accepted for remaining temporary Head to Health Clinics in New South Wales 
and Victoria. An error will be produced for any other organisation. Similarly 
Program Type 3: will always produce an error. While data suppliers must 
ensure the data stored in their systems can be used to meet the PMHC-MDS 
specification that does not place any specific constraints as to how or what 
data organisations store locally, it only places requirements around what 
format data is supplied to the PMHC MDS. Therefore, the Version 5.0 changes 
do not automatically mean that organisations will need to make adjustments 
to their existing source data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, uploads need to be internally consistent. This means that where 
service contact or collection occasion data is modified, the linked episode 
and client must also be included in the upload. Therefore, when uploading in 
Version 5 all existing episodes must use Program Types accepted by the Version 
5.0 specification. Logicly is aware that not being able to continue to submit 
values 2: Head to Health and 3: AMHC for existing episodes may cause issues 
for some organisations and is investigating improvements that would allow 
the submission of the original values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current W1: Universal Aftercare Quarterly Report Template is a simplified 
version of the previous Excel report. A CSV report that is similar to the 
Excel report will be released shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/12/18/Release-of-Version-5-0-for-upload-and-data-entry/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/12/18/Release-of-Version-5-0-for-upload-and-data-entry/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Release of Version 5.0 and scheduled outage for Wednesday 17 December 2025 - 15/12/2025</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Version 5.0 updates explained in the Department of Health, 
Disability and Ageing’s (DoHDA) Circular, which was sent to PHN CEOs on 
Wednesday 19 November 2025, will be released to production during the 
evening of Wednesday 17 December 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Circular has been published at 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/11/19/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Version-5.0-Updates/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/11/19/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Version-5.0-Updates/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be migrating data for the Version 5.0 release on the evening of 
Wednesday 17 December 2025. The PMHC MDS may be unavailable for several 
hours during this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on uploading or entering any data, we advise you to 
complete your work before 8:00pm AEDT on Wednesday 17 December 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you for your patience whilst this work is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/12/15/Release-of-Version-5-0-and-scheduled-outage/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/12/15/Release-of-Version-5-0-and-scheduled-outage/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>FOR ACTION&amp;#58; Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set Version 5.0 Updates</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The below circular was sent to PHN CEOs on Wednesday 19 November 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-----------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear PHN CEOs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular is to inform PHNs and their service providers of forthcoming updates to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS), as part of the Version 5.0 release. These changes are designed to further strengthen data quality, align reporting with evolving national mental health program structures, and support improved monitoring and evaluation across jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff and service providers are aware of the upcoming Version 5.0 release and are subscribed to receive communications
from Logicly’s PMHC MDS support service if they don’t already have a login to the PMHC MDS. If you would like to be added to the 
mailing list please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare to transition data collection and upload arrangements in line with the new Version 5.0 specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the attached document for additional detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any queries please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental Health Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHN CEO Circular&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-version-5&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Version 5&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;overview-2025x11x19&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular provides Primary Health Networks (PHNs) and service providers with information
on updates to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS). These changes
are designed to further strengthen data quality, align reporting with evolving national mental
health program structures, and support improved monitoring and evaluation across
jurisdictions.
To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff and service providers are aware of the upcoming Version 5.0
release and are subscribed to receive communications from Logicly’s PMHC MDS
support service if they don’t already have a login to the PMHC MDS. If you would like to
be added to the mailing list please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare to transition data collection and upload arrangements in line with the new
Version 5.0 specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any questions regarding this information please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;background-2025x11x19&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As outlined in the August 2025 circular to PHNs, the PMHC MDS is undergoing a series of
enhancements to ensure data collection and reporting remain consistent with the evolving
landscape of national mental health programs. The August circular introduced the planned
rebranding of The Way Back Support Service (TWBSS) to Universal Aftercare, as well as the
changes from AMHC and Head to Health to Medicare Mental Health Centres (MMHCs). The
PMHC MDS Version 5.0 data specification release provides further refinements to Program
Types, Funding Sources, and reporting processes to support improved monitoring and
evaluation of these services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-version-50-data-specification&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Version 5.0 Data Specification&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Version 5.0 Data Specification is now available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v5.0/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v5.0/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;key-changes-in-version-50&quot;&gt;Key Changes in Version 5.0&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 5.0 completes the rebranding to MMHC and Universal Aftercare. It includes the
following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare-2025x11x19&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘9: Universal Aftercare’ response will be added to the Program Type field on both the
Intake and Episode tables. This means that Universal Aftercare data will now be
triggered by the Program Type, not by a tag.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seven entirely new tables will be added corresponding to the existing tables in the
Wayback extension. These tables will only need to be submitted where Episodes using
the new ‘9: Universal Aftercare’ Program Type are included&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Episode&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Recommendation Out&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Critical Incident&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Plan&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Needs Identification (NI)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SIDAS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;WHO-5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Existing episodes tagged with !wayback will be migrated to the new Universal Aftercare
Program Type. The !wayback tag will be retained for historical reference only.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new system tag (!uaooh) will be introduced to distinguish episodes under the
Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway Trial. The !uaooh
tag will only be allowed on Episode records where the Program Type is ‘9: Universal
Aftercare’. This tag should be applied to all episodes delivered under the Universal
Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway Trial.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The existing Way Back-specific reports (W1-W4) will be retired and replaced with
updated reports in the standard reports tab:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The W1 report will be converted from a downloadable Excel template to a CSV format.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The W2 report will be retired and a new A series report implemented that shows
the number of episodes that have the Universal Aftercare Program Type but no
linked UA Episode record.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The W3 report that reports on missing TWB Extension data will be converted to a
standard report.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The W4 report that reports on Needs Identification and Recommendation Out
data will be converted to a standard report.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Data Source selector will be updated to remove ‘The Way Back’ and add
‘Universal Aftercare’, based on the new Program Type.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SIDAS and WHO-5 outcome measures will continue to require individual item score
reporting, consistent with previous TWB standards and to support data quality validation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;medicare-mental-health-centres&quot;&gt;Medicare Mental Health Centres&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following changes will be applied to the Program Type field on both the Intake and
Episode tables:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘2: Head to Health’ renamed to ‘2: Head to Health Clinic’. This response is only
to be used by remaining Head to Health Clinics in New South Wales and Victoria.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘3: AMHC’ will be retired. An error will be returned if this response is used.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Existing episodes with Program Type ‘3: AMHC’ will be migrated to Program Type ‘8:MMHC’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Existing episodes with Program Type ‘2: Head to Health’ will be migrated to Program
Type ‘8: MMHC’, excluding:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Former Pop-Up clinics and Head to Health clinics in New South Wales and Australian Capital Territory&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Continuing Head to Health clinics in New South Wales&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Existing/former Pop-Up clinics and Head to Health clinics in Victoria except for the Geelong MMHC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;other&quot;&gt;Other&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new Veteran field will be added to the Intake and Episode tables. This field was
included in The Way Back specification. There is a new IAR-DST variant in development
for Veterans. Veterans will be included on the Intake and Episode tables instead of the
new UA Episode table so that it can be used for monitoring both the IAR-DST and
Universal Aftercare.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new IAR-DST - Practitioner Reason for Override will be added to the IAR-DST table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A New report will allow SDQ, K10/K5, WHO-5, and SIDAS to be reported consistently
across all program types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;transition-period&quot;&gt;Transition Period&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A six-month transition period will be allowed during which the PMHC MDS Version 4.1, The Way
Back Version 3.0 and PMHC MDS Version 5.0 data specifications will all be accepted. After this
transition period, the PMHC MDS Version 4.1 and The Way Back Version 3.0 data specifications
will no longer be able to be uploaded to the PMHC MDS. During the transition period any data
uploaded under either the PMHC MDS Version 4.1 or The Way Back Version 3.0 data
specifications will be migrated to PMHC MDS Version 5.0 data specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-version-50-data-specification-release&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Version 5.0 data specification release&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementation of the PMHC MDS Version 5.0 data specification is currently being finalised
and undergoing quality assurance testing. Logicly will provide information about a release date
via the PMHC MDS mailing list. If you would like to be added to the mailing list, please email
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;action-required-2025x11x19&quot;&gt;Action required&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHNs and their service providers must ensure all relevant staff review this circular and prepare
for the transition to Version 5.0. This includes updating systems and processes to
accommodate the changes. Both Version 5.0 and existing Version 4.1 specifications will be
accepted for a 6-month transition period, after which only Version 5.0 uploads will be
permitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For technical support regarding the PMHC MDS, please contact Logicly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/11/19/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Version-5.0-Updates/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/11/19/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Version-5.0-Updates/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 18/9/2025 (v2.16.3)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2163&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.16.3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.16.3 was released on 
September 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where Episodes were showing as being uncommenced after 
an attended service contact was added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the user management interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug so that adding a user’s first role also authorises them 
to use the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where State and Territory users could not see Provider 
Level aggregation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug that prevent uploads from being filtered by their Upload ID&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A message has been added to the Upload Details to make it explicit 
if the data was processed successfully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/09/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-16-3/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/09/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-16-3/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS and Data Specifications - 18/8/2025 (v2.16.0)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2160&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.16.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.16.0 was released on 
August 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Department of Health, Disability and Ageing’s August 2025 PHN CEO 
Circular, the PMHC MDS has been updated to support the rebranding of 
Adult Mental Health Centres (AMHC) and HeadtoHealth to Medicare Mental 
Health Centres (MMHC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PHN CEO circular has been published at 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/&quot;&gt;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Program Type on both the Intake 
and Episode records&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Head to Health Kids Hubs’ response on Funding Source has been 
renamed to ‘Kids Hubs’ on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Funding Source on the Service 
Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Intake conclusion on the Intake record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Episode conclusion on the Episode record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upload interface now accepts uploads in the Version 4.1.1 data 
specification. The changes in this specification are documented below. 
This version is backwards compatible with the existing Version 4.1.0 
specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trailing white space on sites is automatically trimmed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message when a service contact site is not one of 
the defined sites for the provider organisation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved error messages when columns are missing from the Intake 
file/worksheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message when a duplicate primary service contact 
practitioner is added to a service contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In reports that aggregate by site, changed the aggregation ‘No Site’ 
to ‘Site not defined’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the layout when many data sources are selected so that the 
data sources don’t overflow and overlap with the “Select Report Type” 
heading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users with the Organisation Management or Data Entry roles can define 
or modify the Provider Organisation Sites field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-data-specification-version-411&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specification Version 4.1.1&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Data Specification update v4.1.1 was released on August 18 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates were implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘8: MMHC’ response has been added to Program Type on both the Intake 
and Episode records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Response ‘24: Head to Health Kids Hubs’ on Funding Source has been renamed 
to ‘24: Kids Hubs’ on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘28: MMHC’ response has been added to Funding Source on the Service 
Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘45: MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Intake conclusion on the Intake record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘25: MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Episode conclusion on the Episode record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/08/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-16-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/08/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-16-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>FOR ACTION&amp;#58; Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set upcoming changes for Medicare Mental Health Centres and Universal Aftercare</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The below circular was sent to PHN CEOs on Friday 15 August 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-----------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear PHN CEOs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular is to inform PHNs and their service providers of forthcoming updates to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS), as part of the Version 4.1.1 release. These updates are aligned with ongoing efforts to strengthen data quality, enhance reporting capabilities, and ensure consistency with evolving national mental health program structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this release, enhancements will be made to the way data for Medicare Mental Health Centres (MMHCs) is reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we wish to provide early notice of the upcoming rebranding of The Way Back Support Service (TWBSS) to Universal Aftercare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information provided in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all data for MMHCs is uploaded in accordance with the guidance provided in this circular by 1 October 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all Universal Aftercare data is uploaded to the PMHC MDS in line with relevant guidance provided.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Further guidance regarding Universal Aftercare rebrand will be provided in due course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the attached document for additional detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any queries please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental Health Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHN CEO Circular – August 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;updates-in-the-pmhc-mds&quot;&gt;Updates in the PMHC MDS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;overview-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular is to inform Primary Health Networks (PHNs) and their service providers of
forthcoming updates to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS), as
part of the Version 4.1.1 release. These updates are aligned with ongoing efforts to strengthen
data quality, enhance reporting capabilities, and ensure consistency with evolving national
mental health program structures. As part of this release, enhancements will be made to the
way data for Medicare Mental Health Centres (MMHCs) is reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we wish to provide early notice of the upcoming rebranding of The Way Back
Support Service (TWBSS) to Universal Aftercare. This change reflects that transition away from
Beyond Blue’s oversight of TWBSS is complete in relevant jurisdictions, and arrangements are
now in place to support implementation of universal aftercare services in all states and
territories. Under the National Mental Health and Suicide Prevention Agreement bilateral
schedules, states and territories have flexibility to implement and adapt aftercare service
models to meet the needs of local communities, while contributing to national availability of
aftercare supports. These updates to the PMHC MDS are designed to support improved
monitoring, evaluation, and comparability of services across jurisdictions, and will be
accompanied by updated technical documentation and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information provided in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all data for MMHCs is uploaded in accordance with the guidance provided in this
circular by 1 October 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure all Universal Aftercare data is uploaded to the PMHC MDS in line with relevant
guidance provided.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Further guidance regarding Universal Aftercare rebrand will be provided in due
course.
For any questions regarding this information please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;background-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;mmhcs&quot;&gt;MMHCs&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of July 2025, there are 41 Centres open nationally. Medicare Mental Health Centres provide a
welcoming place where everyone can access free mental health information, services and
supports. Centres are staffed by a team of qualified mental health professionals and people
with lived experience of mental health. Support through the Centres is free for everyone who
walks in the door. Consumers do not need an appointment or a referral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As all Medicare Mental Health Centres have been rebranded, there are new additions to the
available domains in the PMHC MDS which are incorporated under Program Type, Funding
Source and Organisation Type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For policy and funding queries about the Medicare Mental Health Centres program, please
contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Mental.Health.Liaison@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;Mental.Health.Liaison@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Way Back Support Service was originally developed and delivered by Beyond Blue as a trial
suicide aftercare model, with the Australian Government subsequently funding roll-out of this
model in several jurisdictions. Under the National Mental Health and Suicide Prevention
Agreement, the Commonwealth and states and territories agreed to be jointly responsible for
providing aftercare programs, which reflect and respond to local needs and circumstance. This
shift marked the evolution of aftercare services from a specific model, available in some
jurisdictions, to a nationally supported and scalable program now referred to as Universal
Aftercare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reflect this transition, and ensure consistency in data collection and reporting, references to
The Way Back in the PMHC MDS will be rebranded to Universal Aftercare. This includes
introducing a dedicated Universal Aftercare Program Type. This will also include the
introduction of a new tag for the Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral
Pathway Trial. These changes will support improved monitoring, evaluation, and comparability
of aftercare services across jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For policy or funding queries, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SuicidePrevention@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;SuicidePrevention@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;key-changes-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Key Changes&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two data specification updates are planned to implement both the MMHC and Universal
Aftercare changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;version-411-next-planned-release&quot;&gt;Version 4.1.1 (next planned release)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4.1.1 begins the rebranding of AMHC and Head to Health to MMHC. It will include the
following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘8: MMHC’ response will be added to Program Type on both the Intake and Episode
records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Response ‘24: Head to Health Kids Hubs’ on Funding Source will be renamed to ‘24:
Kids Hubs’ on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘28: MMHC’ response will be added to Funding Source on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘45: MMHC’ response will be added to Organisation type referred to at Intake
conclusion on the Intake record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘25: MMHC’ response will be added to Organisation type referred to at Episode
conclusion on the Episode record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4.1.1 is backwards compatible with Version 4.1.0. Only organisations using the above
responses will need to change their uploads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;version-50-to-be-released-end-of-november&quot;&gt;Version 5.0 (to be released end of November)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 5.0 will complete the rebranding to MMHC and Universal Aftercare. It will include the
following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘9: Universal Aftercare’ response will be added to the Program Type field on both the
Intake and Episode tables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seven entirely new tables will be added corresponding to the existing tables in the
Wayback extension. These tables will only need to be submitted where Episodes using
the new ‘9: Universal Aftercare’ Program Type are included&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Episode&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Recommendation Out&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Critical Incident&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Plan&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Needs Identification (NI)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SIDAS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;WHO-5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following changes will be applied to the Program Type field on both the Intake and
Episode tables:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘2: Head to Health’ renamed to ‘2: Head to Health Clinic’. This response is only
to be used by remaining temporary Head to Health Clinics in NSW and Victoria.
Please refer to Program Type for more information&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘3: AMHC’ will be retired. An error will be returned if this response is used&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the following changes will also be included in Version 5.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new Veteran field will be added to the Intake and Episode tables. This field was
included in The Way Back specification. There is a new IAR-DST variant in development
for Veterans. Veterans will be included on the Intake and Episode tables instead of the
new UA Episode table so that it can be used for monitoring both the IAR-DST and
Universal Aftercare&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new IAR-DST - Practitioner Reason for Override will be added to the IAR-DST table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Version 5 is released, existing episodes tagged with !wayback will be migrated to the new
Universal Aftercare Program Type. The !wayback tag will be retained for historical reference
only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uploading of both the new Version 5 specification as well as continued upload of the existing
Version 4.1 specification/Version 3 Wayback extension will be allowed for a 6-month period.
During this period, any data uploaded under the Version 4.1 or Version 3.0 Wayback
specifications will be migrated during the upload process. After the 6-month period, only
Version 5 uploads will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare-outside-of-hospitalexpanded-referral-pathway-trial&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway Trial&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new system tag (!uaooh) will be introduced at the same time as Version 5 to distinguish
episodes under the Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway
Trial. The !uaooh tag will only be allowed on Episode records where the Program Type is ‘9:
Universal Aftercare’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;reporting-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Reporting&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing Way Back-specific reports (W1–W4) will be retired and replaced with updated
reports in the standard reports tab (the W1 report will be converted from a downloadable Excel
template to a CSV format). These will be accessible to PHNs, the Department, and State and
Territory Health Departments/Agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New reports are also in development to support MMHC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;action-required-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Action required&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;mmhcs-1&quot;&gt;MMHCs&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Version 4.1.1 is released, Medicare Mental Health Centres should use the new domains
for Program Type, Funding Source and Organisation Type as outlined above. The Head to Health
or AMHC Program Types should no longer be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medicare Mental Health Centres may wish to amend data retrospectively using these new
domains, but this is not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remaining temporary Head to Health Clinics in NSW and Victoria should not use the new
MMHC domains and continue use of the Head to Health Program Type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare-1&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A draft Version 5.0 specification will shortly be published. PHNs or service providers should
implement changes to their system so that they can start providing data in the Version 5.0
format when it is released. Further guidance will be provided in due course to support a smooth
transition. Once the rebrand is in place, all Universal Aftercare data – including data collected
through the Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway Trial – must be reported using the
Universal Aftercare Program Type in the PMHC MDS. Additionally, data collected as part of the
trial must be tagged with the new identifier to ensure it is easily distinguishable within the
dataset. This will support accurate tracking and analysis of trial-specific outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For technical support regarding the PMHC MDS, please contact Logicly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 6/5/2025 (v2.15.0)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2150&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.15.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.15.0 was released on 
May 6, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;PMHC MDS v4.0 data specification is no longer supported. An error will 
be returned if a file is uploaded in this format.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;headspace v4.0 data specification is no longer supported. An error will 
be returned if a file is uploaded in this format.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the user management interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inviting a user to the PMHC MDS no longer requires the user’s mobile 
phone to be supplied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/05/06/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-15-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/05/06/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-15-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Final reminder of the End of Life for PMHC MDS version 4.0 Data Specification - 28/04/2025</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-reminder-of-the-end-of-life-for-pmhc-mds-version-40-data-specification&quot;&gt;Final reminder of the End of Life for PMHC MDS version 4.0 Data Specification&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS currently supports uploads in both the PMHC version 4.0 format as
documented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&lt;/a&gt;
and the PMHC version 4.1 format as documented at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a final reminder that after the 1st of May 2025 the PMHC MDS will no longer accept uploads using the
Version 4.0 formats. Please ensure that your systems have been migrated to
using the Version 4.1 upload format before this date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A summary of the changes between version 4.0 and 4.1 is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/04/28/Final-PMHC-MDS-Version-4-0-data-specification-end-of-life/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/04/28/Final-PMHC-MDS-Version-4-0-data-specification-end-of-life/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reminder of the End of Life for PMHC MDS version 4.0 Data Specification</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS currently supports uploads in both the PMHC version 4.0 format as
documented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&lt;/a&gt;
and the PMHC version 4.1 format as documented at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the 1st of May 2025 the PMHC MDS will no longer accept uploads using the
Version 4.0 formats. Please ensure that your systems have been migrated to
using the Version 4.1 upload format before this date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A summary of the changes between version 4.0 and 4.1 is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/04/10/Reminder-PMHC-4.0-EOL/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.pmhc-mds.com/2025/04/10/Reminder-PMHC-4.0-EOL/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>