<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>		
		<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS and Data Specifications - 18/89/2025 (v2.16.3)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2163&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.16.3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.16.3 was released on 
September 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where Episodes were showing as being uncommenced after 
an attended service contact was added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the user management interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug so that adding a user’s first role also authorises them 
to use the application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where State and Territory users could not see Provider 
Level aggregation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug that prevent uploads from being filtered by their Upload ID&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A message has been added to the Upload Details to make it explicit 
if the data was processed successfully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/09/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-16-3/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/09/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-16-3/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS and Data Specifications - 18/8/2025 (v2.16.0)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2160&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.16.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.16.0 was released on 
August 18, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the Department of Health, Disability and Ageing’s August 2025 PHN CEO 
Circular, the PMHC MDS has been updated to support the rebranding of 
Adult Mental Health Centres (AMHC) and HeadtoHealth to Medicare Mental 
Health Centres (MMHC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PHN CEO circular has been published at 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/&quot;&gt;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Program Type on both the Intake 
and Episode records&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Head to Health Kids Hubs’ response on Funding Source has been 
renamed to ‘Kids Hubs’ on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Funding Source on the Service 
Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Intake conclusion on the Intake record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Episode conclusion on the Episode record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upload interface now accepts uploads in the Version 4.1.1 data 
specification. The changes in this specification are documented below. 
This version is backwards compatible with the existing Version 4.1.0 
specification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trailing white space on sites is automatically trimmed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message when a service contact site is not one of 
the defined sites for the provider organisation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved error messages when columns are missing from the Intake 
file/worksheet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message when a duplicate primary service contact 
practitioner is added to a service contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In reports that aggregate by site, changed the aggregation ‘No Site’ 
to ‘Site not defined’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the layout when many data sources are selected so that the 
data sources don’t overflow and overlap with the “Select Report Type” 
heading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users with the Organisation Management or Data Entry roles can define 
or modify the Provider Organisation Sites field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-data-specification-version-411&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specification Version 4.1.1&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Data Specification update v4.1.1 was released on August 18 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates were implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘8: MMHC’ response has been added to Program Type on both the Intake 
and Episode records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Response ‘24: Head to Health Kids Hubs’ on Funding Source has been renamed 
to ‘24: Kids Hubs’ on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘28: MMHC’ response has been added to Funding Source on the Service 
Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘45: MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Intake conclusion on the Intake record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘25: MMHC’ response has been added to Organisation type referred to at 
Episode conclusion on the Episode record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/08/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-16-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/08/18/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-16-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>FOR ACTION&amp;#58; Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set upcoming changes for Medicare Mental Health Centres and Universal Aftercare</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The below circular was sent to PHN CEOs on Friday 15 August 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-----------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear PHN CEOs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular is to inform PHNs and their service providers of forthcoming updates to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS), as part of the Version 4.1.1 release. These updates are aligned with ongoing efforts to strengthen data quality, enhance reporting capabilities, and ensure consistency with evolving national mental health program structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this release, enhancements will be made to the way data for Medicare Mental Health Centres (MMHCs) is reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we wish to provide early notice of the upcoming rebranding of The Way Back Support Service (TWBSS) to Universal Aftercare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information provided in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all data for MMHCs is uploaded in accordance with the guidance provided in this circular by 1 October 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all Universal Aftercare data is uploaded to the PMHC MDS in line with relevant guidance provided.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Further guidance regarding Universal Aftercare rebrand will be provided in due course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the attached document for additional detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any queries please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental Health Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHN CEO Circular – August 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;updates-in-the-pmhc-mds&quot;&gt;Updates in the PMHC MDS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;overview-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This circular is to inform Primary Health Networks (PHNs) and their service providers of
forthcoming updates to the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS), as
part of the Version 4.1.1 release. These updates are aligned with ongoing efforts to strengthen
data quality, enhance reporting capabilities, and ensure consistency with evolving national
mental health program structures. As part of this release, enhancements will be made to the
way data for Medicare Mental Health Centres (MMHCs) is reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we wish to provide early notice of the upcoming rebranding of The Way Back
Support Service (TWBSS) to Universal Aftercare. This change reflects that transition away from
Beyond Blue’s oversight of TWBSS is complete in relevant jurisdictions, and arrangements are
now in place to support implementation of universal aftercare services in all states and
territories. Under the National Mental Health and Suicide Prevention Agreement bilateral
schedules, states and territories have flexibility to implement and adapt aftercare service
models to meet the needs of local communities, while contributing to national availability of
aftercare supports. These updates to the PMHC MDS are designed to support improved
monitoring, evaluation, and comparability of services across jurisdictions, and will be
accompanied by updated technical documentation and guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information provided in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all data for MMHCs is uploaded in accordance with the guidance provided in this
circular by 1 October 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ensure all Universal Aftercare data is uploaded to the PMHC MDS in line with relevant
guidance provided.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Further guidance regarding Universal Aftercare rebrand will be provided in due
course.
For any questions regarding this information please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;MentalHealthData@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;background-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;mmhcs&quot;&gt;MMHCs&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of July 2025, there are 41 Centres open nationally. Medicare Mental Health Centres provide a
welcoming place where everyone can access free mental health information, services and
supports. Centres are staffed by a team of qualified mental health professionals and people
with lived experience of mental health. Support through the Centres is free for everyone who
walks in the door. Consumers do not need an appointment or a referral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As all Medicare Mental Health Centres have been rebranded, there are new additions to the
available domains in the PMHC MDS which are incorporated under Program Type, Funding
Source and Organisation Type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For policy and funding queries about the Medicare Mental Health Centres program, please
contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Mental.Health.Liaison@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;Mental.Health.Liaison@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Way Back Support Service was originally developed and delivered by Beyond Blue as a trial
suicide aftercare model, with the Australian Government subsequently funding roll-out of this
model in several jurisdictions. Under the National Mental Health and Suicide Prevention
Agreement, the Commonwealth and states and territories agreed to be jointly responsible for
providing aftercare programs, which reflect and respond to local needs and circumstance. This
shift marked the evolution of aftercare services from a specific model, available in some
jurisdictions, to a nationally supported and scalable program now referred to as Universal
Aftercare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reflect this transition, and ensure consistency in data collection and reporting, references to
The Way Back in the PMHC MDS will be rebranded to Universal Aftercare. This includes
introducing a dedicated Universal Aftercare Program Type. This will also include the
introduction of a new tag for the Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral
Pathway Trial. These changes will support improved monitoring, evaluation, and comparability
of aftercare services across jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For policy or funding queries, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SuicidePrevention@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;SuicidePrevention@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;key-changes-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Key Changes&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two data specification updates are planned to implement both the MMHC and Universal
Aftercare changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;version-411-next-planned-release&quot;&gt;Version 4.1.1 (next planned release)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4.1.1 begins the rebranding of AMHC and Head to Health to MMHC. It will include the
following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘8: MMHC’ response will be added to Program Type on both the Intake and Episode
records.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Response ‘24: Head to Health Kids Hubs’ on Funding Source will be renamed to ‘24:
Kids Hubs’ on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘28: MMHC’ response will be added to Funding Source on the Service Contact record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘45: MMHC’ response will be added to Organisation type referred to at Intake
conclusion on the Intake record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘25: MMHC’ response will be added to Organisation type referred to at Episode
conclusion on the Episode record&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4.1.1 is backwards compatible with Version 4.1.0. Only organisations using the above
responses will need to change their uploads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;version-50-to-be-released-end-of-november&quot;&gt;Version 5.0 (to be released end of November)&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 5.0 will complete the rebranding to MMHC and Universal Aftercare. It will include the
following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘9: Universal Aftercare’ response will be added to the Program Type field on both the
Intake and Episode tables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seven entirely new tables will be added corresponding to the existing tables in the
Wayback extension. These tables will only need to be submitted where Episodes using
the new ‘9: Universal Aftercare’ Program Type are included&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Episode&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Recommendation Out&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Critical Incident&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Plan&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UA Needs Identification (NI)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;SIDAS&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;WHO-5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following changes will be applied to the Program Type field on both the Intake and
Episode tables:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘2: Head to Health’ renamed to ‘2: Head to Health Clinic’. This response is only
to be used by remaining temporary Head to Health Clinics in NSW and Victoria.
Please refer to Program Type for more information&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;‘3: AMHC’ will be retired. An error will be returned if this response is used&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the following changes will also be included in Version 5.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new Veteran field will be added to the Intake and Episode tables. This field was
included in The Way Back specification. There is a new IAR-DST variant in development
for Veterans. Veterans will be included on the Intake and Episode tables instead of the
new UA Episode table so that it can be used for monitoring both the IAR-DST and
Universal Aftercare&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new IAR-DST - Practitioner Reason for Override will be added to the IAR-DST table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Version 5 is released, existing episodes tagged with !wayback will be migrated to the new
Universal Aftercare Program Type. The !wayback tag will be retained for historical reference
only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uploading of both the new Version 5 specification as well as continued upload of the existing
Version 4.1 specification/Version 3 Wayback extension will be allowed for a 6-month period.
During this period, any data uploaded under the Version 4.1 or Version 3.0 Wayback
specifications will be migrated during the upload process. After the 6-month period, only
Version 5 uploads will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare-outside-of-hospitalexpanded-referral-pathway-trial&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway Trial&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new system tag (!uaooh) will be introduced at the same time as Version 5 to distinguish
episodes under the Universal Aftercare Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway
Trial. The !uaooh tag will only be allowed on Episode records where the Program Type is ‘9:
Universal Aftercare’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;reporting-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Reporting&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existing Way Back-specific reports (W1–W4) will be retired and replaced with updated
reports in the standard reports tab (the W1 report will be converted from a downloadable Excel
template to a CSV format). These will be accessible to PHNs, the Department, and State and
Territory Health Departments/Agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New reports are also in development to support MMHC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;action-required-2025x08x15&quot;&gt;Action required&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;mmhcs-1&quot;&gt;MMHCs&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Version 4.1.1 is released, Medicare Mental Health Centres should use the new domains
for Program Type, Funding Source and Organisation Type as outlined above. The Head to Health
or AMHC Program Types should no longer be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medicare Mental Health Centres may wish to amend data retrospectively using these new
domains, but this is not mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remaining temporary Head to Health Clinics in NSW and Victoria should not use the new
MMHC domains and continue use of the Head to Health Program Type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;universal-aftercare-1&quot;&gt;Universal Aftercare&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A draft Version 5.0 specification will shortly be published. PHNs or service providers should
implement changes to their system so that they can start providing data in the Version 5.0
format when it is released. Further guidance will be provided in due course to support a smooth
transition. Once the rebrand is in place, all Universal Aftercare data – including data collected
through the Outside of Hospital/Expanded Referral Pathway Trial – must be reported using the
Universal Aftercare Program Type in the PMHC MDS. Additionally, data collected as part of the
trial must be tagged with the new identifier to ensure it is easily distinguishable within the
dataset. This will support accurate tracking and analysis of trial-specific outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For technical support regarding the PMHC MDS, please contact Logicly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/08/15/FOR-ACTION-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-upcoming-changes-for-Medicare-Mental-Health-Centres-and-Universal-Aftercare/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 6/5/2025 (v2.15.0)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2150&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.15.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.15.0 was released on 
May 6, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;PMHC MDS v4.0 data specification is no longer supported. An error will 
be returned if a file is uploaded in this format.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;headspace v4.0 data specification is no longer supported. An error will 
be returned if a file is uploaded in this format.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the user management interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inviting a user to the PMHC MDS no longer requires the user’s mobile 
phone to be supplied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/06/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-15-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/05/06/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-15-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Final reminder of the End of Life for PMHC MDS version 4.0 Data Specification - 28/04/2025</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;final-reminder-of-the-end-of-life-for-pmhc-mds-version-40-data-specification&quot;&gt;Final reminder of the End of Life for PMHC MDS version 4.0 Data Specification&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS currently supports uploads in both the PMHC version 4.0 format as
documented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&lt;/a&gt;
and the PMHC version 4.1 format as documented at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a final reminder that after the 1st of May 2025 the PMHC MDS will no longer accept uploads using the
Version 4.0 formats. Please ensure that your systems have been migrated to
using the Version 4.1 upload format before this date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A summary of the changes between version 4.0 and 4.1 is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/28/Final-PMHC-MDS-Version-4-0-data-specification-end-of-life/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/28/Final-PMHC-MDS-Version-4-0-data-specification-end-of-life/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reminder of the End of Life for PMHC MDS version 4.0 Data Specification</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS currently supports uploads in both the PMHC version 4.0 format as
documented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/&lt;/a&gt;
and the PMHC version 4.1 format as documented at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the 1st of May 2025 the PMHC MDS will no longer accept uploads using the
Version 4.0 formats. Please ensure that your systems have been migrated to
using the Version 4.1 upload format before this date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A summary of the changes between version 4.0 and 4.1 is available at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/upgrading-from-previous-versions.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/10/Reminder-PMHC-4.0-EOL/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/04/10/Reminder-PMHC-4.0-EOL/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 28/03/2025 (v2.14.12)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v21412&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.14.12&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.14.12 was released on 
March 28, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Department of Health and Aged Care and State organisations can now 
view the A1, B1, B2 and B3 reports down to the Provider Organisation 
reporting level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented in the data extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implemented a fix to allow a PHN user to download data from a headspace 
provider organisation within their PHN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message when 09099999 is provided on an Intake for 
either Referral date or Date Client Contacted Intake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/03/28/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-14-12/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/03/28/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-2-14-12/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>FOR ACTION&amp;#58; Tags in the PMHC MDS</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The below circular was sent to PHN CEOs on Friday 20 February 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-----------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear PHN CEOs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Health and Aged Care is writing to you to request that all PHNs and/or their Provider Organisations (POs) conduct a review of the tags they use in the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS) to ensure they have been entered correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information provided in this circular regarding
review of PMHC MDS tags by 31 March 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amend any tags that have been entered incorrectly in the PMHC MDS by 30 June 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all tags, historically and new, are entered in accordance with the guidance provided 
in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any questions regarding this information please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mentalhealthdata@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;mentalhealthdata@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental Health Data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PHN CEO Circular – February 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tags-in-the-pmhc-mds&quot;&gt;Tags in the PMHC MDS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;overview-2025x02x20&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department of Health and Aged Care (the department) is writing to you to request that all PHNs and/or their Provider Organisations (POs) conduct a review of the tags they use in the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS) to ensure they have been entered correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support the information in this circular, PHNs are asked to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure relevant staff receive and review the information provided in this circular regarding
review of PMHC MDS tags by 31 March 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amend any tags that have been entered incorrectly in the PMHC MDS by 30 June 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure all tags, historically and new, are entered in accordance with the guidance provided 
in this circular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any questions regarding this information please contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mentalhealthdata@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;mentalhealthdata@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some issues have been identified in relation to the tag field in the PMHC MDS. There are two types of tags available to users in the PMHC MDS; &lt;em&gt;system&lt;/em&gt; tags that start with “!” and &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt; tags that do not start with “!”. &lt;em&gt;System&lt;/em&gt; tags beginning with an exclamation mark (!) are reserved for use by the department only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;System&lt;/em&gt; tags have been used to implement extension data specifications such as Wayback (!wayback) and headspace (!headspace). They have also been used to record data where extra partitioning of data was needed for reporting purposes. An example of this was for the bushfire response in 2020. A !br20 tag was implemented to track episodes where one or more services were funded through the bushfire response. The current list of reserved system tags is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/reserved-tags.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4/reserved-tags.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;User&lt;/em&gt; tags can be used by PHNs/POs to tag records in order to partition data to accommodate local requirements as desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;action-required&quot;&gt;Action required&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHNs and their POs are asked to review and audit their tags in the PMHC MDS to ensure they have been entered correctly (e.g., no missing commas between tags). Of particular note, multiple tags can be added to a record by separating them with commas. Some of the existing tags may have been meant to have been multiple tags, but they have not been comma separated, so instead one long tag has been added. For example a record may have a tag ‘!covid19 this is an example !br20’ whereas the intention was to have the three tags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;!covid19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;this is an example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;!br20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags can contain lower case letters (or will get lowercased), numbers, dashes, spaces, and “!”. Leading and trailing spaces will be stripped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 1 May 2025 the PMHC MDS will only accept system tags that are in the reserved list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For technical support, please contact Logicly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/02/20/FOR-ACTION-Tags-in-the-PMHC-MDS/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/02/20/FOR-ACTION-Tags-in-the-PMHC-MDS/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 20/12/2024 (v2.14.7)</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v2147&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v2.14.7&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v2.14.7 was released on 
December 20, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the PMHC MDS interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Tools menu can now be accessed by keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been applied in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An error is returned when a site is included on a Service Contact 
that is not defined for the Provider Organisation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An error is returned if there is PHN data in uploads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The A1, B1, B2 and B3 reports have been updated to support the sites
field that was added in the PMHC MDS Version 4.1 Data Specification.
For more information about this field please refer to
&lt;a href=&quot;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2024/10/27/New-Sites-Field-in-the-PMHC-MDS/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2024/10/27/New-Sites-Field-in-the-PMHC-MDS/&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/data-model-and-specifications.html#service-contact-site&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/projects/data-specification/en/v4.1/data-model-and-specifications.html#service-contact-site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State users can now view reports down to Provider Organisation level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guides have been updated to reflect these updates. They are available
at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/12/20/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-14-7/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/12/20/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-and-Data-Specifications-v-2-14-7/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS - Change to login workflow - introduction of MFA - 16/10/2024</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;As per our recent communication, to enhance data security Logicly will be 
releasing the new Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) login workflow change 
on Monday 11th November 2024. The details sent originally are included again below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@logicly.com.au&quot;&gt;support@logicly.com.au&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC-MDS team at Logicly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-change-to-login-workflow&quot;&gt;PMHC-MDS - Change to login workflow - introduction of MFA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Logicly’s ongoing commitment to data security and in response to
the Australian Signals Directorate’s Information Security Manual guidance, 
we are rolling out Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) to all users that 
access the PMHC-MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-what-is-changing&quot;&gt;What is changing?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After entering your username and password you will be required to complete 
a second authentication step. MFA is an additional layer of authentication 
that works by requiring users to provide verification information (via a 
device they have) in addition to their email address/password (which they 
know) when logging in. Taken together these multiple “factors” are used 
to verify the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logicly’s authentication system supports a variety of additional factors, 
including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push notifications sent to an application on the user’s smart mobile 
device&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One-time passcodes generated by an application such as Google 
Authenticator and entered by the user during login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB Security Keys which support WebAuthn with FIDO. These are connected 
to the users computer and touched during login&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have a user guide that will help step users through different options 
and how to set them up: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.logicly.com.au/en/latest/mfa-user-guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://docs.logicly.com.au/en/latest/mfa-user-guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-when-will-this-happen&quot;&gt;When will this happen?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logicly intends to release this change on 11th November 2024.  A reminder 
email will be sent in the days prior to the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;mfa-reminder-why-is-this-happening&quot;&gt;Why is this happening?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change is being made in order to meet security improvements around the 
authentication and authorisation process for the PMHC-MDS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@logicly.com.au&quot;&gt;support@logicly.com.au&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions or issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC-MDS team at Logicly&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/11/06/PMHC-MDS-Reminder-of-change-to-login-workflow-introduction-of-MFA/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/11/06/PMHC-MDS-Reminder-of-change-to-login-workflow-introduction-of-MFA/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>