<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>		
		<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.pmhc-mds.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 25/8/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.15.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.15.0 was released on August 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An SLK generator within the client data entry forms has been implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provider Organisations can now be uploaded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Error messages have been made more descriptive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Items 11-13 of the K10+ have been changed from text input to drop down fields.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fields in the client data entry form have been reorganised to group related fields.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fields in the practitioner data entry form have been reorganised to group related fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guide has been updated to reflect these updates. It is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/08/25/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-15-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/08/25/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-15-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS outage on Wednesday 30 August 2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS outage on Wednesday 30 August 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to our regular system maintenance which occurs fortnightly on Wednesdays in the period 9:00pm-12:00pm AEST, we will also be upgrading the database systems next Wednesday and as such our maintenance period will start an hour earlier at 8:00pm AEST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such,  the PMHC MDS will be unavailable sometime in the period 8:00pm - 12:00pm AEST on Wednesday 30 August, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on using any of the data products during this time, we advise you to complete your work before 8:00pm AEST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you for your patience whilst this maintenance is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/08/25/PMHC-MDS-outage-2017-08-30/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/08/25/PMHC-MDS-outage-2017-08-30/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 28/7/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.14.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.14.0 was released on July 28, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A ‘Reporting’ tab has been added. Users who have been granted the ‘Reporting’ role will be able to see this tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category E - Reports for data managers to monitor data supply - have been implemented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Data Extract’ tab has been moved to be a sub tab of the ‘Reporting’ tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Client - Client Key - no longer editable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Client - Organisation Path - no longer editable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service Contact - Practitioner - Only practitioners associated with the Provider Organisation responsible for providing the service to the client will be listed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users should no longer be unexpectedly timed out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following upload errors have been fixed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Episodes without a referral date that have collection occasions with a measure date will no longer generate an error.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;K10+ and K5 collection occasions can now have both item scores and a total recorded, provided the item scores match the total. An error will be generated where the item scores and total do not match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guide has been updated to reflect these updates. It is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;ATAPS MDS to PMHC MDS data mapping&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ATAPS MDS to PMHC MDS data mapping documentation at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/ataps/ataps-pmhc-mapping.html&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/ataps/ataps-pmhc-mapping.html&lt;/a&gt; has been updated to show the mapping of ATAPS MDS diagnosis fields to PMHC Principal Diagnosis and Additional Diagnosis where two ATAPS diagnosis fields have been specified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/28/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-14-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/28/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-14-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 21/7/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.13.3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.13.3 was released on July 21, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validation has been changed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#episode-source-of-cash-income&quot;&gt;Episode - Source of Cash Income&lt;/a&gt; so that responses other than ‘0: N/A - Client aged less than 16 years’ can be used if a client is less than 16 years of age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validation has been changed on &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#client-proficiency-in-spoken-english&quot;&gt;Client - Proficiency in Spoken English&lt;/a&gt; so that responses other than ‘0: Not applicable (persons under 5 years of age or who speak only English)’ can be used if a client is less than 5 years of age or if they speak only English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/21/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-13-3/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/21/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-13-3/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 20/7/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.13.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.13.2 was released on July 20, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who have been granted the ‘Data Entry’ role can now add and edit K10+ and K5 information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Upload tab has been made more responsive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guide has been updated to reflect these updates. It is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/20/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-13-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/20/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-13-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS and Data Specifications - 11/7/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.12.3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.12.3 was released on July 11, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been implemented::&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ‘Client Data’ tab has been renamed ‘Data Entry’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Practitioners sub tab has been moved out of the Organisations tab and into the Data Entry tab. This resolves an issue where users who only had the ‘Data Entry’ role could not add/edit Practitioners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.10&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.10 was released on July 7, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following data item has been added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data model and specifications
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data model
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Updated data model diagram following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pmhc-mds.com/communications/#/2017/06/21/FOR-INFORMATION-and-ACTION-PHN-CEO-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Update/&quot;&gt;Department of Health communication on 21 June, 2017&lt;/a&gt; regarding the Master Client Index&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/11/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v0-12-3-and-Data-Specifications-v1-0-10/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/07/11/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v0-12-3-and-Data-Specifications-v1-0-10/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS and Data Specifications- 30/6/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.12.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.12.0 was released on June 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following functionality has been added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client, Episode and Service Contact information can now be added and edited for users who have been granted the ‘Data Entry’ role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.9&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.9 was released on June 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following data item has been added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data model and specifications
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Record formats
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#provider-organisation-data-elements&quot;&gt;Provider Organisation&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#provider-organisation-status&quot;&gt;Added Organisation Status&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/30/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v0-12-0-and-Data-Specifications-v1-0-9/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/30/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v0-12-0-and-Data-Specifications-v1-0-9/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Release of the ATAPS MDS to PMHC MDS data mapping and update to the PMHC Data Specifications</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;Release of the ATAPS MDS to PMHC MDS data mapping&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that the ATAPS MDS to PMHC MDS data mapping was released on June 26, 2017 and is now available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/ataps/ataps-pmhc-mapping.html&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/ataps/ataps-pmhc-mapping.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHNs who are implementing new client systems and mapping the ATAPS data to PMHC data need to ensure that their data mapping conforms with this mapping specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note: we are still in the process of investigating the mapping of ATAPS diagnoses fields to PMHC Principal Diagnosis and Additional Diagnosis fields where multiple ATAPS diagnosis fields have been selected. In order to allow PHNs to access this mapping in a timely manner we are releasing it without having finished this investigation. Further announcements will be made when this investigation is complete.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.8&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.8 was released on June 26, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following data items have been updated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data model and specifications
  &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Record formats
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Episode
      &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#episode-principal-diagnosis&quot;&gt;Episode - Principal Diagnosis&lt;/a&gt; to add the following response codes:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;100: Anxiety disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;200: Affective (Mood) disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;300: Substance use disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;400: Psychotic disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#episode-additional-diagnosis&quot;&gt;Episode - Additional Diagnosis&lt;/a&gt; to add the following response code:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;000: No additional diagnosis&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;100: Anxiety disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;200: Affective (Mood) disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;300: Substance use disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;400: Psychotic disorders (ATAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Service Contact
      &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#service-contact-type&quot;&gt;Service Contact - Type&lt;/a&gt; to add the following response code:
        &lt;ul&gt; 
          &lt;li&gt;98: ATAPS&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/26/Release-of-the-ATAPS-MDS-to-PMHC-MDS-data-mapping-and-update-to-the-PMHC-Data-Specifications-v1-0-8/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/26/Release-of-the-ATAPS-MDS-to-PMHC-MDS-data-mapping-and-update-to-the-PMHC-Data-Specifications-v1-0-8/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>INFORMATION and ACTION&amp;#58; PHN CEO - Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set Update</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;The below circular was sent to PHN CEOs on Tuesday 20 June 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-----------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear PHN CEOs,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1 July 2017, PHNs are expected to be uploading data into the Primary Mental Health Care Minimum Data Set (PMHC MDS). The following provides CEOs an update on the transition to full compliance and the master client index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Transition to Full Compliance&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous communications have indicated that the existing Access to Allied Psychological Services (ATAPS) / Mental Health Services in Rural and Remote Areas (MHSRRA) MDS would be shut down when the PMHC MDS data entry interface was implemented. Due to difficulties in converting the data between the two systems, the ATAPS/MHSRA system will continue until further notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1 July 2017, full compliance with the PMHC MDS is still expected. However, this means all consenting clients referred for mental health services from 1 July 2017 have information entered into the PMHC MDS. Existing clients whose data has been entered into the ATAPS / MHSRRA MDS may continue to do so. However, new referrals should NOT be entered into the ATAPS / MHSRRA MDS from 1 July 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Options for reporting and transferring active ATAPS referrals into the new PMHC MDS have been considered by the PMHC MDS Working Group and three options have been agreed for addressing the needs. Each PHN must choose only one option, their preferred option, of the three presented below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once selected, please have your PMHC MDS Data Primary User advise your preferred option to Strategic Data at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@pmhc-mds.com&quot;&gt;support@pmhc-mds.com&lt;/a&gt; by 1 July 2017. Strategic Data will then work with the PHN on their preferred option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Option one&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ATAPS / MHSRRA MDS will be kept online for up to 12 months to allow for those existing client referrals already receiving services under the old ‘ATAPS’ system to be maintained until all sessions associated with that referral are complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option requires PHNs and their organisations to work with two data collections, ie: The PMHC MDS for new clients / episodes commencing post 1 July 2017 and the old ATAPS system for existing clients who have not completed their treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Option two&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategic Data will provide the PHN an &lt;i&gt;ATAPS MDS data extract in PMHC MDS upload format&lt;/i&gt;. The extract will contain ATAPS clients and their associated data where a client had an associated session in the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that, ATAPS does not associate clients with provider organisations, which is a structural element required for the PMHC MDS. Therefore, the organisation path in this extract will be empty and the PHN will need to assign each client to their correct provider organisation. Any other data which cannot be mapped from ATAPS to PMHC data definitions will be set as missing. Each record will have the ‘!ATAPS’ tag added so records exported from ATAPS can be identified in future analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This option will require significant work by the PHN to assign provider organisations to each client and significant amounts of missing data on the migrated clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Option three&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where PHNs are implementing new clients systems, they may choose to map the ATAPS data to PMHC data and then upload to the PMHC MDS directly from their client system. PHNs choosing this option will be provided with specifications of the &lt;i&gt;mapping of ATAPS to PMHC format&lt;/i&gt; being used to produce the ATAPS MDS data extract at option two. This option requires PHNs to follow this mapping format to provide consistency in mapped ATAPS data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Master Client Index&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current PMHC MDS specification requires a Client Key that is unique and stable at the PHN regional level, not at the provider organisation level. The purpose of the Master Client Index is to help PHNs and their provider organisations manage client information across the PHN region. This requirement has proven problematic for PHNs and is being worked through by the PMHC MDS Working Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine what issues exist with managing the client key and possible solutions, nine PHNs worked with Strategic Data to describe their models for triaging patients, the information systems being used by PHNs and provider organisations, the ease of updating information systems and resources available for manual reconciliation of clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of this work, a Master Client Index is not possible at this time, and as such, will not be a requirement for full compliance from 1 July 2017. The requirement will now be organisational uniqueness instead of regional level uniqueness until this can be addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC Working Group agrees that the opportunity for national and regional level uniqueness is an aspiration and will continue to be investigated by the Department. The Department is currently looking into the use of Healthcare Identifiers and will provide you with updates as this work progresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any further queries, please email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mentalhealthdata@health.gov.au&quot;&gt;mentalhealthdata@health.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Mental Health Data and Funding Section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Mental Health Services Branch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Health Services Division&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Department of Health&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/21/FOR-INFORMATION-and-ACTION-PHN-CEO-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Update/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/21/FOR-INFORMATION-and-ACTION-PHN-CEO-Primary-Mental-Health-Care-Minimum-Data-Set-Update/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS Service Provider Quick Reference Guide - 19/6/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4&gt;The PMHC MDS Service Provider Quick Reference Guide Version 1.1  was released on June 19, 2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Service Provider QUICK REFERENCE Guide is a resource intended to describe key issues and concepts related to the collection of, and provision of data to, the PMHC MDS for mental health service providers. For more detailed information regarding the PMHC MDS, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specifications&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two versions of the PMHC MDS Service Provider Quick Reference Guide. If you are a service provider, it is recommended that you use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pmhc-mds.com/doc/service-provider-quick-reference-guide-20170619.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF version&lt;/a&gt; produced by the Department of Health. If you are a Primary Health Network, you can use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pmhc-mds.com/doc/service-provider-quick-reference-guide-template-20170619.docx&quot;&gt;word version&lt;/a&gt; to tailor some of the information to your local context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PMHC MDS Service Provider Quick Reference Guide has been updated to correct links to the PMHC MDS documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/19/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-Service-Provider-Quick-Reference-Guide-v1-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/06/19/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-Service-Provider-Quick-Reference-Guide-v1-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>