<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>		
		<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 13/3/2018</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0221&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.22.1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.22.1 was released on March 13, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A3-1 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Client data - Summary,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A3-2 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Client data - Detail,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A4-1 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Episode data - Summary,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A4-2 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Episode data - Detail,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A5-1 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Service Contact data - Summary,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A5-2 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Service Contact data - Detail,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A6-1 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Practitioner data - Summary, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A6-2 - Data Quality Report: Missing and invalid Practitioner data - Detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Data Entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug when editing Episodes where the Save button was not enabled and no error message was shown when the Episode End Date was set to 09/09/9999.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug when editing Collection Occasions where an error would be shown when the Measure Date was set to 09/09/9999.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed the age based validation on Client - Proficiency in Spoken English. This validation will be replaced with a future data quality report.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed the age based validation on Episode - Source of Cash Income. This validation will be replaced with a future data quality report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Data Extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby the ‘Select Organisation’ drop down was not showing the correct organisations for users who only have roles at a Provider Organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name of the A2 report has been changed from ‘A2: Volume Trends’ to ‘A2: Monthly Volume Trends’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where files with an extremely large number of empty lines would cause the upload pipeline to hang.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed the age based validation on Client - Proficiency in Spoken English. This validation will be replaced with a future data quality report.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed the age based validation on Episode - Source of Cash Income. This validation will be replaced with a future data quality report.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added an Upload ID to the View Uploads table and the Upload Details page. This ID is unique to each upload. Reporting this ID when contacting the Helpdesk will allow support staff to locate problem uploads easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2018/03/13/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-22-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2018/03/13/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-22-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 15/2/2018</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0211&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.21.1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.21.1 was released on February 15, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented across the MDS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby errors on login would be removed before they could be read.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where the headers and footers would flash on login, logout and refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby if you were logged into the PMHC MDS in one tab/window and then you opened another tab/window you would be shown the login screen, instead of automatically being logged in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Data Entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where collection occasion measures dates before 1/1/2016 were not being flagged as invalid before being saved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where a collection occasion measure date was recorded as missing (09099999) against a closed episode, would be incorrectly flagged as invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Data Extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby the ‘Select Organisation’ drop down was not showing the correct organisations for users who only have roles at a Provider Organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where a collection occasion measure date was recorded as missing (09099999) against a closed episode, would be incorrectly reported as an error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby the current date was showing as invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2018/02/15/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-21-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2018/02/15/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-21-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS and Data Specifications - 19/1/2018</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v021&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.21&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the first PMHC MDS update for 2018. PMHC MDS Update
v0.21 was released on January 19, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented across all interfaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After a user has logged in, smaller headers and footers will be shown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minimum dates have been applied to the following fields: Client - Date of
Birth, Episode - End Date and Referral Date, Service Contact - Service
Contact Date, Collection Occasion - Measure Date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the Data Entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Referral Date has been added to the Episode Summary information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the Upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The username of the user that uploaded a file is now shown in the
‘View Uploads’ table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the Reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The title of a report now indicates if the ‘Include only records with
Client Consent’ flag was checked when generating the report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the Data Extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An ‘Associated Date Rules Explained’ link has been added to explain the
‘Include data without associated dates’ checkbox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Data Entry
interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby if you edited a record in such a way that an error was
returned and then navigated back to the ‘View’ tab, you would see the
edited, unsaved data, not the data that is actually stored in the PMHC MDS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the ‘Add New Client’ form whereby if the ‘The Client Key
already exists.’ error has been shown, it would remain when the ‘Client Key’
field had been cleared.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the ‘Add New Service Contact’ form whereby an error relating
to the ‘Postcode’ field would remain when the field had been cleared.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the Client ‘Edit Details’ form where the ‘Save’ button would
be active even when the SLK needed to the regenerated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in the Episode ‘Details’ tab where the orange ‘Suicide Referral’
bar was not being shown when the ‘Suicide Referral Flag’ was set to ‘Yes’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Users interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby an error relating to the ‘Mobile’ field would remain
when the field had been cleared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the Upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug whereby the ‘Organisation’ field in the ‘Upload A File’ form
was being sorted by organisation key, not organisation name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guide has been updated to reflect these updates. It is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-data-specifications-update-v1012&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update v1.0.12&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Data Specifications Update
v1.0.12 was released on January 19, 2018. The following updates have been
implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html&quot;&gt;Data model and specifications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#record-formats&quot;&gt;Record formats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#client-data-elements&quot;&gt;Client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#client-date-of-birth&quot;&gt;Client - Date of Birth&lt;/a&gt; to specify that the date of birth must
not be before 1 January 1900.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#episode-data-elements&quot;&gt;Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#episode-end-date&quot;&gt;Episode - End Date&lt;/a&gt; to specify that the episode end date must
not be before 1 January 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#episode-referral-date&quot;&gt;Episode - Referral Date&lt;/a&gt; to specify that the episode referral
date must not be before 1 January 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#service-contact-data-elements&quot;&gt;Service Contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#service-contact-date&quot;&gt;Service Contact - Date&lt;/a&gt; to specify that the service contact
date must not be before 1 January 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#outcome-collection-occasion-data-elements&quot;&gt;Outcome Collection Occasion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/data-model-and-specifications.html#collection-occasion-measure-date&quot;&gt;Collection Occasion - Measure Date&lt;/a&gt; to specify that the measure
date must not be before 1 January 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2018/01/19/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-21-0-and-Data-Specifications-v1-0-12/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2018/01/19/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-21-0-and-Data-Specifications-v1-0-12/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 12/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0202&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.20.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.20.2 was released on December 22, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented across all interfaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Context sensitive help links have been provided.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop downs for selecting organisations have been made more consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An ‘Include only records with Client Consent’ option has been added to reports so that organisations can 
generate reports which include the same data as reports that are generated for the Department of Health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Data Extract’ tab has been moved from being a subtab of the ‘Reports’ tab. It is now it’s own separate top-level tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The design of the reports tab has been cleaned up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A problem with the ‘Include data without associated dates’ checkbox has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 12/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0200&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.20.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.20.0 was released on December 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A1 - High level summary of overall volumes, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A2 - Monthly volume trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where an error was reported when requesting a Data Extract.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where data extracts for a provider organisation included all data for other provider organisations the user had the reporting role assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where an error was produced when an existing episode was closed and a new episode was opened for the same client in a single upload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/12/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/12/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 08/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0190&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.19.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.19.0 was released on
December 8, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An uneditable, prepopulating Organisation Path field has been added to the
Add Provider Organisation form so that users can see what the Organisation
Path will be before saving the new Provider Organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to make data entry more efficient, errors for duplicate keys will
now be shown when entering data into the key input field instead of after
clicking save.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tables now show ‘Loading…’ when a page is waiting for data to load.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the order of organisations in the Data Extraction ‘Select Organisations’ drop down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the order of organisations in the Upload ‘Organisation’ drop down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where an error would be returned when viewing records with ‘/’ or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; in the key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where if 0 was provided as an SDQ subscale the value was changed to 99.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where ‘Showing results for “”’ would appear under the Client Search form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in the “Invite New User” form when inviting a user that already exists with the PMHC MDS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where clicking ‘Practitioners’ in the breadcrumbs would take you to the ‘Client’ tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where new clients weren’t being added to the existing search results table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where updated client details were not being displayed after clicking save.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where users with the User Management role were not seeing organisations under the Organisations tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SDQ subscales will now be validated against the supplied Total Difficulties Score.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in uploads when trying to upload to an inactive organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in uploads when the organisation key was not consistent with the organisation path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/08/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-19-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/08/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-19-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 01/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0182&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.18.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.18.2 was released on
December 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where trailing blank lines in files were causing system errors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where blank lines within SDQ data would cause subtotal validation to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all users who were affected by these issues, we thank you for your patience and we sincerely apologise for any inconvenience these issues had caused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/01/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/12/01/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS system and network upgrades on Saturday 9 December 2017 - 29/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;On 22 November 2017 we sent out an announcement that there would be a PMHC MDS system and network upgrade on Saturday 2 December between 10:00am and 2:00pm AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this upgrade has been delayed. We will now be performing system and network upgrades on Saturday 9 December between 10:00am and 2:00pm AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not expect any outage, but there is the possibility that an outage may
occur during this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on uploading or entering any data during this time, we
advise you to complete your work before 10:00am AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you for your patience whilst this work is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/11/29/PMHC-MDS-system-and-network-upgrades-on-Saturday-9-December-2017/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/11/29/PMHC-MDS-system-and-network-upgrades-on-Saturday-9-December-2017/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 24/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0181&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.18.1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.18.1 was released on
November 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data entry
interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where Internet Explorer users could not login.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all users who were affected by this issue, we thank you for your patience
and we sincerely apologise for any inconvenience this issue has caused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/11/24/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/11/24/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 23/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0180&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.18.0&lt;/h4&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/11/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2017/11/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>