<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>		
		<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.pmhc-mds.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 12/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0202&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.20.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.20.2 was released on December 22, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented across all interfaces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Context sensitive help links have been provided.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop downs for selecting organisations have been made more consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An ‘Include only records with Client Consent’ option has been added to reports so that organisations can 
generate reports which include the same data as reports that are generated for the Department of Health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the reports interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘Data Extract’ tab has been moved from being a subtab of the ‘Reports’ tab. It is now it’s own separate top-level tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The design of the reports tab has been cleaned up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A problem with the ‘Include data without associated dates’ checkbox has been fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 12/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0200&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.20.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.20.0 was released on December 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented in the reporting interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A1 - High level summary of overall volumes, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System report A2 - Monthly volume trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data extract interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where an error was reported when requesting a Data Extract.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where data extracts for a provider organisation included all data for other provider organisations the user had the reporting role assigned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where an error was produced when an existing episode was closed and a new episode was opened for the same client in a single upload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/12/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/12/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-20-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 08/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0190&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.19.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.19.0 was released on
December 8, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An uneditable, prepopulating Organisation Path field has been added to the
Add Provider Organisation form so that users can see what the Organisation
Path will be before saving the new Provider Organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to make data entry more efficient, errors for duplicate keys will
now be shown when entering data into the key input field instead of after
clicking save.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tables now show ‘Loading…’ when a page is waiting for data to load.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data entry interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the order of organisations in the Data Extraction ‘Select Organisations’ drop down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the order of organisations in the Upload ‘Organisation’ drop down.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where an error would be returned when viewing records with ‘/’ or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;?&lt;/code&gt; in the key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where if 0 was provided as an SDQ subscale the value was changed to 99.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where ‘Showing results for “”’ would appear under the Client Search form.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in the “Invite New User” form when inviting a user that already exists with the PMHC MDS.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where clicking ‘Practitioners’ in the breadcrumbs would take you to the ‘Client’ tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where new clients weren’t being added to the existing search results table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where updated client details were not being displayed after clicking save.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error where users with the User Management role were not seeing organisations under the Organisations tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SDQ subscales will now be validated against the supplied Total Difficulties Score.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in uploads when trying to upload to an inactive organisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in uploads when the organisation key was not consistent with the organisation path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/08/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-19-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/08/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-19-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 01/12/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0182&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.18.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.18.2 was released on
December 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where trailing blank lines in files were causing system errors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where blank lines within SDQ data would cause subtotal validation to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all users who were affected by these issues, we thank you for your patience and we sincerely apologise for any inconvenience these issues had caused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/01/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/12/01/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS system and network upgrades on Saturday 9 December 2017 - 29/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;On 22 November 2017 we sent out an announcement that there would be a PMHC MDS system and network upgrade on Saturday 2 December between 10:00am and 2:00pm AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this upgrade has been delayed. We will now be performing system and network upgrades on Saturday 9 December between 10:00am and 2:00pm AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not expect any outage, but there is the possibility that an outage may
occur during this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on uploading or entering any data during this time, we
advise you to complete your work before 10:00am AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you for your patience whilst this work is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/29/PMHC-MDS-system-and-network-upgrades-on-Saturday-9-December-2017/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/29/PMHC-MDS-system-and-network-upgrades-on-Saturday-9-December-2017/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 24/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0181&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.18.1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.18.1 was released on
November 24, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data entry
interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where Internet Explorer users could not login.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all users who were affected by this issue, we thank you for your patience
and we sincerely apologise for any inconvenience this issue has caused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/24/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-1/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/24/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-1/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 23/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0180&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.18.0&lt;/h4&gt;

</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-0/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/22/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-18-0/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS system and network upgrades on Saturday 2 December 2017 - 22/11/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;We will be performing system and network upgrades on Saturday 2 December
between 10:00am and 2:00pm AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not expect any outage, but there is the possibility that an outage may
occur during this period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on uploading or entering any data during this time, we
advise you to complete your work before 10:00am AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you for your patience whilst this work is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/22/PMHC-MDS-system-and-network-upgrades-on-Saturday-2-December-2017/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/11/22/PMHC-MDS-system-and-network-upgrades-on-Saturday-2-December-2017/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Update to the PMHC MDS - 25/10/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;pmhc-mds-update-v0172&quot;&gt;PMHC MDS Update v0.17.2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that PMHC MDS Update v0.17.2 was released on
October 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following features have been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deletion of records via both the data entry interface and uploads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the data entry
interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restricted the use of the ‘Complex Care Package’ Principal Focus of Treatment
Plan to the three selected Lead PHNs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue where the Suicide Referral icon was showing on episode
summaries where the Suicide Referral Flag was set to ‘Unknown’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an issue with the User Invite form where users could be invited to a
Provider Organisation with the Organisation Management role. This role is
restricted to PHN level.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added the Episode Key onto the Collection Occasion details/edit forms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changed the sorting of Country of Birth and Main Language Spoken at Home so
that the top ten languages/country of births as reported in the 2011 census
are moved to the top of the list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The service contact postcode field is now prefilled with 9999 for all non
Face to Face modalities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an bug where the “Unknown” option was not being given for Suicide
Referral Flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following updates and bugfixes have been implemented in the upload
interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed an error in uploads when there was no practitioners file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restricted the use of the ‘Complex Care Package’ Principal Focus of Treatment
Plan to the three selected Lead PHNs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message ‘Collection date must not be after Episode end
date’ so that it includes information about the episode key and collection
occasion key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved the error message ‘Client may not have multiple open episodes. This
client has an existing open episode within this organisation’ so that it
includes information about the client key and episode keys.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Split the error message ‘Invalid episode_completion_status on row [x]. Where
service contact - final is recorded as “No further services planned” the
episode completion status should be recorded using one of the treatment
concluded responses.’ so that one message is returned when an episode has
a completion status but no end date and another error is returned when an
episode has an end date but no completion status.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Improved error messages like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;…organisation_path / client_key value of “…” is invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;…organisation_path / episode_key value of “…” is invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;…organisation_path / practitioner_key value of “…” is invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return a sensible error instead of “episode: new row for relation “episode”
violates check constraint “end_after_referral” / Failing row contains (…).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return a sensible error instead of “client: new row for relation “client”
violates check constraint “past_date” / Failing row contains (…).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user guide has been updated to reflect these updates. It is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/user-documentation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deleting-records-in-the-pmhc-mds&quot;&gt;Deleting records in the PMHC MDS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deletion of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Episodes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collection Occasions, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practitioners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is now possible via both the data entry interface and uploads. Organisations
cannot be deleted. The upload specification has been updated to describe the
format for deleting records via uploads. It is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/upload-specification.html#deleting-records&quot;&gt;https://docs.pmhc-mds.com/data-specification/upload-specification.html#deleting-records&lt;/a&gt;.
File format changes to accommodate deletion are backwards compatible with the
current format.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/10/25/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-17-2/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/10/25/Update-to-the-PMHC-MDS-v-0-17-2/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PMHC MDS outage on Tuesday 10 October 2017 - 6/10/2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>&lt;p&gt;We will be performing urgent system maintenance on Tuesday 10 October between 6:30-7:30am AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, the PMHC MDS upload service will be unavailable sometime in the above period. Data Entry and Reporting functionality will still be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are planning on uploading any data during this time, we advise you to complete your work before 6:30am AEDT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you for your patience whilst this maintenance is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/10/06/PMHC-MDS-outage-on-Tuesday-10-October-2017/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.pmhc-mds.com/2017/10/06/PMHC-MDS-outage-on-Tuesday-10-October-2017/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>